Online EdD from Baylor - Now accepting applications for Baylor's online Doctor of Education program. 廣告 ...



Aaron Wiegel, Ph.D. • 3 度

Data Scientist

美國 舊金山灣區

傳送訊息



Synthego Corporation



University of California, Berkeley



查看聯絡資料



🔐 500+ 位聯絡人

I am a data scientist who is interested in the challenge of working with non-standard data, especially text data, to generate unique insights that drive decision making.

With a PhD in chemical physics, years of research and programming experience, and a passion for learning, I enjoy combining data from diverse sources and ideas from different disciplines to uncover hidden value in data.

I am particularly interested in working with companies in fields such as customer service/CRM, healthcare, biotech, and environmental monitoring/sensors or on natural language processing-related projects in any industry.

I have several years experience coding in Python using common data science packages (numpy, scipy, matplotlib, sci-kit learn, etc.) In addition, from my experience on a team of volunteer community college instructors in San Quentin State Prison, I learned communication, teamwork, and flexibility in a constantly evolving environment.

Check out my blog at https://aawiegel.github.io to see descriptions of some of the projects I have worked on.

Background Overview

- Data Scientist at Metis
- Postdoctoral Fellow at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory
- Graduate Student Researcher at UC Berkeley
- PhD, 2013, University of California Berkeley, Physical Chemistry
- BS, 2006, University of Wisconsin Madison, Chemistry, Technical Japanese

Skills

Linear Algebra, Statistics, Natural Language Processing, and Machine Learning in Python (Numpy, Scipy, pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib, gensim, nltk, keras, TensorFlow, Flask) Computing Skills: Linux CLI, AWS

Statistical Analysis of both observational and experimental datasets

Extensive experience working with physical measurements and numerical simulations

Hobbies:

促銷內容



Online EdD from **Baylor**

Now accepting applications for Baylor's online Doctor of Education program.





Drowning in Student Debt?

Your student loans don't define you. Let's get you a better way to pay.

您可能也想看看



Oren Tevet • 3 度 Data Scientist | Bioengineer



Aniket Aranake • 3 度 Data Scientist



Emily Miller • 3 度 Data Scientist



Katherine Luna • 3 度 Data Scientist



Data Scientist



Jeff Kao • 3 度 Data Scientist



Olivia Warren • 3 度 Data Scientist at Synthego Corporation



Vladimir Lazovskiy • 3 度 Data Science & Analytics



Sukeerthi Varadarajan...

Data Scientist | Analytics | Machine Learning



Shen Ma • 3 度 Data Scientist

Home brewing beer Cooking Running Board Games

Other Organizations American Homebrewers Association Prison University Project



How to recommend dog breeds using deep learning -

顯示較少 へ

促銷內容



Online EdD from Baylor

Now accepting applications for Baylor's online Doctor of Education program.

深入暸解



Drowning in Student Debt?

Your student loans don't define you. Let's get you a better way to pay.

要點整理

聯絡Aaron ······

提供無償諮詢、志工服務。

傳送訊息給Aaron

文章和活動

580 人關注



So you want to be a data scientist

Aaron Wiegel, Ph.D. LinkedIn 文章

Update 2018–08–28: After spending 9 months as a professional data scientist, I updated this article to reflect some other reflections I had. With all the hype ar更多

38 個讚 • 7 則回應

凸 讚 □ 回應 😝 分享

全部文章

I updated this article I wrote about a year ago with some new

Aaron分享 6 Likes • 1 Comment

所有動態

工作經歷

Data Scientist

Synthego Corporation

2018 年 1 月 一 目前 · 10 個月 Redwood City, California

Using instrument and facilities data to help optimize and evaluate the performance of an automated synthesis laboratory

Data Scientist

Metis

Metis

2017 年 6 月 — 2017 年 12 月 · 7 個月 San Francisco Bay Area

A selective, 12-week data science boot camp.

Project Summaries (Learn more at my blog at https://aawiegel.github.io):展間

Freelance Editor

Cactus Communications

2016年5月-2017年12月·1年8個月

Worked under tight deadlines to provide nearly error-free English and scientific language edits to the manuscripts of ESL scientists

Postdoctoral Researcher

Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory

2014年1月-2017年5月·3年5個月 Berkeley, CA

Developed custom Python classes to transform and analyze 1 GB+ of complex data from stochastic kinetics simulations of particulate matter oxidation

Cleaned and analyzed experimental data to ensure accurate comparison between... 展開

University of California, Berkeley

7年7個月

Graduate Student Researcher

2006年10月-2013年12月·7年3個月

Synthesized model predictions, atmospheric observations, and experimental data to provide insights into the oxygen isotope cycle in the ozone layer

Experimental methods: Photochemistry experiments, isotope ratio mass spectro... 展開

Graduate Student Instructor

2006年6月-2008年5月・2年

GSI (TA) for three different courses in three semesters and 2 summer sessions.

Chemistry 3B (Organic Chemistry) Summer 2006, Summer 2007, Fall 2007: supervised students in lab, graded lab reports, term papers, and exams, conducted review s... 展開

+3 ~

教育背景

University of California, Berkeley

PhD, Physical Chemistry, Atmospheric Chemistry 2006 年 -2013 年

活動和社團: Graduate student instructor (TA) for three courses in three semesters and two summer sessions, Graduate Student Researcher Ellman group fall 2006 to spring 2007, Graduate Student Researcher Boering group

fall 2007 to winter 2013, Short Stay Fellowship in spring 2010 (3mo) doing research at IMAU in the Netherlands

Research Boering group, Kinetic isotope effects in ozone formation and their photochemical transfer to carbon dioxide through O(1D)-mediated isotope exchange. Atmospheric observations of trace gases. Kinetic isotope effects in nitrous oxide formation in corona discharge.

University of Wisconsin-Madison

BS, Chemistry, Technical Japanese 2002 年 - 2006 年

活動和社團: Research in 2003 in the Nathanson group, research in 2005 to 2006 in the Zimmerman group, Japanese language for 6 semesters, technical Japanese for 2 semesters, studied abroad in 2005 in Japan for 2 months in the summer through Princeton in Ishikawa program, tutored first generation college students through TRIO program in Japanese from 2005 to 2006

Undergraduate research with Nathanson group: Using bulk physical properties to understand surface interactions

Undergraduate research with Zimmerman group: Photochemistry and synthesis of aromatic ketones

志工經歷



Prison University Project 2013 年 1 月 - 目前 • 5 年 10 個月 教育

Taught college courses to San Quentin Prison inmates through Patten University. Classes I've taught include Introduction to Statistics and Probability, Geology, Precalculus, and Intermediate Algebra.





